ed3000 出品
温柔点  汉娜
Be gentle, Hannah.
我们以您的尊名召唤您来助我们一臂之力
We invoke you by your great names to come to our aid.
击败罗马人
Defeat the Romans.
摧毁他们的战船  攻城器械和士兵
Destroy their ships, their engines of war, and their soldiers.
我们终将胜利
We will prevail.
汉娜
Hannah.
你今天没有献祭
You did not make an offer today.
我更想献祭一个罗马人
I prefer to sacrifice a Roman.
你在哪里  我就在哪里
Where you are, I am too.
你在哪里  我永远都在  吾妻
And where you are, I am too, forever, my wife.
风太大了
The wind is too strong.
收帆划桨
Furl sail and strike water.
Furl sail, strike water.
收帆划桨
Furl sail and strike water.
划桨
Strike water.
他们的土地都是抢来的
They have no lands but the ones they've stolen.
他们所到之处  皆是破坏  却美其名曰和平
Wherever they go, they need destruction and call it peace.
这是非洲最后一座自由之城  诺瓦
This is the last free city in Africa, Nova.
今日我们将奋战
Today, we go into battle.
祈祷你的神与你同在
Pray that your God is with you.
若不在  他就不是神
If he is not, he is no god.
我们无所畏惧
We've nothing to fear.
死亡存在时  我们不在
But death is, we are not.
我们存在时
But we are.
死亡便不存在
Death is not.
保持阵型  听我指令
Stay together and listen for my command.
抬头挺胸站起来
Rise up with your head out.
射击
Release.
升起攻城塔
Raise the tower.
回到前面
Back in front.
带上装备快跑
Let's run with your stuff.
杀手
Killer.
我会等你
I'll wait for you.
我以罗马的荣光宣布占领这座城市
I claim this city for the glory of rule.
祈祷吧  维克图斯
Pray, Victus.
去和谈判判吧
Go to the Concord.
他们对你做了什么
What damage have they done you?
怎么了
What's up?
还有伤口吗
Other shots?
对不起  我的孩子
I'm sorry, my son.
我时日无多了
I have not long.
这条船带我们去的地方  我无法忍受
This galley is sailing us to something I cannot endure.
我已准备好去另一个地方了
I am ready to be taken to another place.
再等一年吧
A year a while longer.
我还记得你第一次被带到我们身边时的样子
I remember well when you first were brought to us.
一个来自沙漠的孤独男孩  天真而又害怕
A lonely boy from the desert, guileless, afraid.
你接受了我们教授的一切
You embraced everything we taught you.
你找到了阿瑞莎特的爱
You found Arishat's love.
你的灵魂得到了滋养
Your soul was replenished.
当我死后  我的祖先会在来世迎接我
When I die, my ancestors will meet me in the next world.
谁会迎接你
Who will meet you?
我知道
I know.
我已经尽了
I am done.
不要让他们改变你的本性
Do not let them change what you are.
我能看到那个孩子
I can see this boy.
暴民
The mob!
你必须独自前行了  哈努克
You must go alone now, Hanuk.
永远不要让他们找到你
Never let them find you.
走吧
Go.
盖托皇帝
Emperor Gator.
卡拉肯皇帝
Emperor Karakon.
阿卡西斯将军
General Acasis.
我已夺取了你的米迪安和你的名声
I have taken you, Midian, your names.
但你的统治或将超越所有前任皇帝
But your dominion may eclipse that of every emperor that came before you.
我与劳雷尔的兄弟同在
And I'm with Laurel's brother.
为庆祝你的征服  竞技场将举行比赛
In honor of your conquest, there will be games in the colosseum.
这是为我举行比赛的要求
A requirement of games in my honor.
为元老院和罗马人民服务已是莫大的荣耀
Serving the Senate and the people of Rome is honor enough for me.
你太谦虚了  阿卡西斯
You are too modest, Acasis.
这不适合像你这样功勋卓著的将军
It does not suit a general as accomplished as yourself.
荣耀属于您  而非我
The glory is yours, not mine.
我只想离开罗马  与妻子共度时光
I only ask for some respite from Rome to spend time with my wife.
你的妻子  是的
Your wife? Yes.
记得我们给予她的特权吗
Remember the privileges we have granted her?
在这样的场合她为何不在
Where is she now to ignore such an occasion?
胜利尚未完全到来
There are victories yet still to come.
波斯
Persia.
印度
India.
都必须征服
Both must be conquered.
罗马已有众多臣民
Rome has so many subjects.
她必须养活他们
She must feed them.
他们还能吃更多
They can eat more.
你的胜利将被铭记  作为罗马人民伟大的见证
Your triumphs will be celebrated as a tribute to the greatness of the Roman people.
野兽与角斗士的主人
Madness of beasts, master of gladiators.
诸神与议员们
Ye gods and the town councilors.
尊贵的宾客们
Distinguished guests.
安提亚的公民们
Got high on the back citizens of Antia.
看看罗马征服的敌人的下场
Behold the fate of the conquered enemies of Rome.
波帕利安  你们这些蠢货和他们的首领
The Popalian, you idiots and their chief term,
诸神在上
you gods!
这个很有意思
This one is interesting.
我要开火
I'll fire.
希望如此
Hope, go to that.
将军
General.
夫人
My lady.
感谢诸神让你平安归来
I thank the gods that brought you back home safe.
我感谢保护我的军队
I thank the army they protected me.
让我为你准备食物
Let me feed you.
走
Go.
竞技场是神圣的殿堂
The arena is a sacred temple.
对最勇敢的人来说  通往荣耀之路就在竞技场
For the bravest of you, the road to glory runs through the arena.
竞技场让奴隶成为角斗士  让角斗士获得自由
The arena turns slaves into gladiators and gladiators into free men.
你们有虫子
You have worms.
我认识这个人
I know this one.
他吃猴子
He eats monkeys.
去吧  坐下  吃饭
Go, sit. Eat.
你
You.
我知道  起来
I know. Get up.
你的母语是什么  我都会说
What is your native language? I speak them all.
你不回答  是因为你不能  或是不愿
You don't answer because you can't, because you won't.
好吧
All right.
暴力是通用的语言
Violence is the universal language.
埃戈  让他试试身手
For ego, put him through his paces.
他能打猿猴  让我们看看他能否对抗人类
He can fight an ape. Let's see if he can fight a man.
很好
Very good.
制服他
Close him down.
把他带到我面前
Bring him to me.
啊
Ah!
下巴很硬朗
A strong jaw.
臂力不错
Good arms.
气味更好闻
Better smell.
你会成功的
You will do well.
这是一门艺术
It is an art.
挑选角斗士
Choosing gladiators.
有人选择表演者
Some choose entertainers.
有人选择蛮力
Some choose brute force.
我选择愤怒
I choose rage.
观众喜欢鲜血 也喜欢和他们一样渴望鲜血的人
Crowd loves blood, and they love those who love blood as much as they do.
而你 我的朋友 愤怒
And you, my friend, rage,
如同涌泉般从你身上
pours out of you like...
像奶水一样
like milk.
从马乳头流出
From a horse tit.
你会成为出色的战士
You will be quite the fighter.
不是为了你
Not for you.
你说得对 你不是为我而战
You're right. You do not fight for me.
我让你进入竞技场 你要么战斗 要么死亡 由你选择
I put you in the ring. You fight or you die. The choice is yours.
但我能给你谁的头颅
But whose head could I give you
才能平息你的怒火
that would satisfy this fury?
整个罗马军队
The entire Roman armies.
太多了
Too much.
那位将军就够了
The general rule will do.
将军
General.
奥卡西奥将军
General Ocasio.
为我效力发泄怒火
Use your rage in my service,
你就能得到他的头颅 供你砍下
and you will have his head ready for your sword.
服从我 他就会臣服于你 拒绝我
Serve me and he'll serve you. Deny me.
你就会死
And you will die.
有时我希望你顺从我 而不是为他们打仗
At times I will wish you to bend on me rather than fight their wars.
我已经做出选择
I've made my choice.
我能接受
I can live with it.
但我对那两个人已经失去耐心
But my patience with those two is at an end.
待会再说
Later.
你现在可以回房间了
You may go to your quarters now.
我们什么都不需要
We need nothing in.
听着新米底安海滩上妻子母亲们为死者哀嚎
To hear wives and mothers mauling their dead on that beach at New Midian.
西拉
Silla.
不能再这样了
No more.
我不会再让年轻人为他们的虚荣心送命
I will not waste another generation of young men for their vanity.
如果我要再打一场仗 那就是推翻他们
If I fight another campaign, it must be to depose them.
你的军队什么时候到
When will your troops arrive?
十天内就能登陆
We landed austere in ten days.
有多少人只忠于你一人
How many of them will be loyal to you alone?
全部
All of them.
皇后并无民心
The empress do not have the support of the people.
人民厌倦了疯狂和暴政
The people are weary of the madness, the tyranny.
罗马的梦想是什么
What is the dream of Rome?
如果我们的人民不自由
If our people are not free?
我们是自由的
We are free.
放纵自由
To excess.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们是自由的
We are free.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢 抱歉 天哪
Thank you. Excuse me, my goodness.
我就知道行省满足不了你
I knew the provinces were not enough for you.
我只是来参加宴会
I'm just here for the gays.
你不会失望的
You won't be disappointed?
罗马有你这样的人喜欢的一切游戏
Rome has all the gangs that men like you like to play.
像我们这样的人 弱者 像我们
Men like me, frags, men like us.
我知道罗马没有什么事能瞒过你
I know nothing happens in Rome unless you tasted it first.
这就是我来这里的目的
That's my purpose here.
我们会找到的 你懂的
We'll find out so you know.
听说你有意
What's this we hear about you being interested in
参选元老院 我的朋友
standing for an election to the Senate, my friend?
我
Me?
你知道我是谁吗 鲍勃
You know who I am, Bob?
我连算盘都不会用 但这个我懂
I don't even know how to use an abacus, but I do understand that.
在这些宴会上 客人们惯常会下注
It's customary for your guests to make wages at these favors.
你想下多少
How large a sum did you have in mind?
一千金币以示敬意
Thousand gold in honor.
两千
Two.
Two?
拒绝
Denial.
退后
Stand back!
诸位皇帝陛下 贵族们 女士们先生们
My emperors, lords, ladies and gentlemen, and
还有元老们 献上一场格斗艺术
senators, for your entertainment, the art of combat.
我为您呈现 蛮族人对战我的得意门生 威猛的文森
May I present the barbarian versus from my own stable, the mighty Vincen!
这是你的最后
This is your la
三个回合 肉搏战
Three rounds, hand to hand.
用剑
Swords!
我们要看他们拿剑决一死战
We want swords to fight to the death.
不许求饶或放水
No quarter to be offered or given.
开始战斗
Fight now!
兄弟 别为他们的娱乐而互相残杀
Brother, let's not kill each other for their amusement.
精彩
Remarkable!
特拉克斯 你看起来很贵重
Trax, you looked expensive for her.
恭喜
Congratulations.
谢谢
Thank you.
精彩
Remarkable.
从我的卫队里来的
From my detail.
说话
Speak.
我说让他说话 他来自殖民地
I said speak is from the colonies, Your
陛下 他只懂母语
Majesty, his native tongue is all he understands.
地狱之门日夜敞开
The gates of hell are open night and day.
下坠平滑 道路最易
Smooth is the descent and easiest away.
但要从地狱返回 重见
But to come back from hell and to view the
晴朗天空 这才是艰巨的任务
cheerful skies in this, the task and mighty labor lies.
维吉尔的诗 陛下
Vergil, Your Majesty.
诗歌
Poetry!
太聪明了 天哪
Very clever, my goodness.
谢谢
Thank you.
我本很无聊 但你让我惊喜
I'm so bored, but you surprised me.
取悦您是我唯一的愿望
To amuse you is my only wish.
朕很满意
We are amused.
我们都期待看到你的诗人在竞技场表现
And we all look forward to seeing your poet perform in the arena.
我也是 陛下
As do I, Your Majesties.
谢谢
Thank you.
贝戈
Bego.
跟我来
Come with me.
今天你打得不错 也很幸运
You fought well today, but you were lucky too.
你背诵的诗句
The lines you recited.
不是在非洲学的 我知道
You didn't learn that in Africa, I know that.
好诗能传得很远
A good verse travels far.
谁教你诗歌的
Who taught you poetry?
一个被俘的罗马军官
A captured Roman officer.
我看守他时 他常讲故事打发时间
I was posted guard over and he used to tell us tales to pass the time.
那个囚犯后来怎样了
And what became of this prison?
我们把他吃了
How we ate him.
像蛮族人那样
As barbarians do.
你出生在哪里
And where were you born?
如果我注定要在竞技场为你而死 过去又有什么关系
Why does my past matter if it is my future to die for you in the arena?
为了罗马的金钱诉说你的幸存故事
Telling what you survived for Roman money.
角斗士可以赎回自由
A gladiator can buy his own freedom.
获得解放
His liberty.
罗马梦
The Roman dream.
奴隶梦想的不是自由 而是拥有自己的奴隶
The slave dreams not of freedom, but of a slave to call his own.
西塞罗
Cicero.
这就是你的成长之道 马克里穆斯
Is that what you were raised on, Macrimus?
为了罗马的金钱你做了什么
What did you have to do for Roman money?
你答应给我一个头颅
You promised me a head.
好好干  你想要谁的头都行
Earn your keep and you can have anyone's head.
天父  守护并指引我们
Father, protect us and guide us.
诸位议员
Senators.
我的名字
My name.
希望能在更好的时机与诸位相见
I lay think I wish you a meeting in better times.
好日子终会来临
Better times will come.
我们在此是为了夺回这座城市
And why are we here to take back the city?
让罗马重返昔日荣光
And restore Rome to where she should be.
令人振奋的计划
An exciting venture.
在竞技最后一天  我的军队将听我号令
When, on the final day of the games, my army waits for my commanded austere.
五千名忠于我的士兵
Five thousand soldiers loyal to me.
会进入罗马和竞技场  在那里将皇帝兄弟
Will enter Rome and then the coliseum where they will arrest the emperors for their
以危害元老院和人民的罪名逮捕
crimes against the senate and their people.
这计划很大胆  风险也很大
This plan is ambitious and risky.
罗马将由你们管理和
Rome will be yours to administer and to...
马库斯·奥勒留曾说过要让权于
Marcus Aurelius talked of restoring power to the
元老院  但那已是上一代的事  情况大不相同
senate, but that was a generation ago, much as change.
人民已多年未见希望
The people have not seen hope for many years.
但只要有时间和引导
But with time and guidance.
露西拉  你是马库斯·奥勒留的女儿  他有我的忠诚
Lucilla, you are the daughter of Marcus Aurelius. He had my loyalty.
你也有
And so do you.
特拉克斯议员
Senator Thraxx.
政治追随权力  夫人
Politics follows power, my lady.
夺回属于您的一切  元老院就会支持您
Take back what is rightfully yours and the senate will support you.
谢谢
Thank you.
他们告诉我这个地方时  从未提过这臭味
When I was told of this place, I never mentioned the stink.
那是汉娜的味道
That would be Hannah.
在我离开前  你得忍着点
Well, you'll have to put up with me as I act.
楼上没人看见  一只狼
No one saw up there. A wolf.
那对双胞胎是弃婴  被遗弃在山上等死
The twins there, they were outcasts. Left from the hills to die.
那头母狼发现了他们  用奶水喂养他们
That wolf found them, she suffered them on a mill.
被野兽养大  这血脉里就带着
Raised by an animal, it's in their blood.
你怎么知道这地方的
How do you know this place?
我知道他们带来的混乱
I know the chaos they brought.
这座城市污染了它触及的一切
This city infects everything it touches.
我从未想过它会这么大
I never dreamt it would be so big.
别被它迷惑  这座城市病入膏肓
Don't fall for it. This city is diseased.
啊  特拉克斯
Ah, Thraxx.
关于我们的报酬
About our wages.
啊  佣金  我没忘  我向来按时付账
Ah, the barbarium. I haven't forgotten. I always repay my wages.
我只是想建议  也许你的
I'm merely going to suggest that perhaps your
运气会改变  不如来场双倍或一空
luck might change, shall we say, double or quits.
列队  列队
Line up. Line up.
成列  成列
Line, line.
卡蒂卡拉皇帝
Emperor Katicala.
盖托皇帝
Emperor Gator.
罗马的子民们
Citizens of Rome.
这神圣的竞技是为庆祝罗马战胜野蛮人而举办
These sacred games are held to honor the victory of Rome over the fans of humanity.
开始  开始
Go! Go!
也是为了表彰罗马的统帅  尤瑟夫·阿卡西尔将军
And to honor Rome's knee-degree commander, General Yosuf Akasiel.
与他一同的是尤西拉  马库斯·奥勒留皇帝的女儿
And with him, Yosilah, the daughter of Emperor Marcus O'Ladius.
凯撒
cases
将军
General
我不是演说家  也不是政客
I am not an orator or a politician.
我是个士兵
I am a soldier.
我在战场上见过男男女女的勇气  甚至在这竞技场也曾见过
I have seen bravery in men and women during war, and even once in this arena.
如果你们要向众神祈求什么  就祈求这样的勇气吧
So if you ask anything of the gods, ask for that same bravery.
因为罗马现在需要这勇气
Because Rome needs it now.
来自山脉
From the mountains,
来自蜗牛
from the snails,
来自坚果
from the macronuts,
来自女主人
from the mistress.
来自卡蒂卡拉皇帝和盖托皇帝的马厩
From the snails of Emperor Katicala and Gator themselves,
不败的冠军
the undefeated champion,
毁灭者吉赛尔
Giselle the Destroyer.
向凯撒致敬
Hail, Caesars!
保持阵型  等冲锋时就往墙边突围
Hold together and win a charges break for the wall.
舒拉在哪
Where's Shula?
坚持
Hold!
冲锋
Cows!
兄弟  那是诗人吗
Brother, is that poet, is it not?
我记不清了  一切都很模糊
I can't remember, and I was a blur.
地狱之门昼夜开放
The gates of hell are open night and day.
平坦的下坡路  我忘了后面的
Smooth as the descent, I forget.
平坦的下坡路
Smooth as the descent.
平坦的下坡路  他看见了前路
Smooth as the descent, he sees the way.
鲜血
Blood.
是谁
Who's that?
我们要施以仁慈吗
Shall we shall mercy?
仁慈
Mercy.
不予仁慈
No mercy.
众神饶恕了你的性命
Your life has been spared by the gods.
我很快会夺走你的剑  接受破碎的仁慈
I will soon efface your blade, and accept broken mercy.
通往自由的路不在竞技场  而是通向这里
The road to freedom doesn't run through the arena, leads to this.
照顾好你们自己
Go to yourselves.
地狱之门昼夜开放
Gates of hell are open night and day.
平坦的下坡路  他看见了前路
Smooth as the descent, he sees the way.
玻璃之门是孤独的身影
Gates of glass is the figure alone.
这将结束我们的计划
It's going to end our agenda.
卢修斯安全了
Lucius is safe.
卢修斯
Lucius.
卢修斯  你现在是王位唯一的继承人
Lucius, you're the soul who add to the throne now.
有人想杀你夺取权力
There are men who want to kill you so they can take power.
等安全了我就把你接回来  母亲  你为什么不能和我一起走  我得留在这里  为了你  也为了罗马
I promise I'll bring you back as soon as I'm safe. Mother, why can't you come with me? I have to stay here for your sake, and for the sake of Rome.
记住你是谁  记住我爱你
Remember who you are, and that I love you.
我也爱你
I love you.
快来  快来
Come on.  Come on.
那么  你叫什么名字
So, what's your name?
我是莱利  我的女儿
I'm Riley, my daughter.
当然了  死于伤口感染的比死在竞技场的还多
Of course, more men die of infected wounds than they are in the arena.
这需要清理  需要缝合  会很痛
This needs to be cleaned, needs to be stitched, and it's going to hurt.
这是狄波拉的呼吸和鸦片
This is Deborah's breath and opium.
用来止痛的
It's for the pain.
你该吸一口
You should breathe in.
现在疼痛持续太久  他们甚至已经感觉不到了
And the pain is so long now, they don't even notice anymore.
截肢的数量我都数不清了
There are more amputations than I can count.
你是怎么学会这门手艺的
How did you learn your trade?
你问什么
What did you ask?
我的手法太重
I got a heavy hand.
我曾是个角斗士
I used to be a gladiator myself.
在我巅峰时期 你觉得能打赢我吗
What would you have bested me in your prime force?
以你现在的状态 我现在就能打赢你
In your current state, I could best you now.
你很幸运 我已放下剑戟
Luckily for you, I have put down my sword, so I
如今我选择救人而不是杀人
will spend my days saving lives instead of taking them.
年纪这么大 我的声音都变了
My voice has changed so late in life.
我们今生的所为 将在永恒中回响
What we do in life echoes in eternity.
我好像知道他们是谁
I feel like I know who those were.
我的队长名号写在其中一座墓上
My captain credit is written on one of the tombs.
与一位角斗士的遗骨同在
With the bones of a gladiator.
我的冠军 我永不安息
My champion, I shall never rest.
我的冠军 你听到观众的欢呼了吗
My champion, did you hear that crowd?
听到他们的欢呼了吗
Did you hear that crowd?
你有一种特质
You have something.
我从一开始就知道
I know it from the start.
是勇气
The jalapenos.
没错 希腊人称之为激情 烈焰 愤怒
Yes, the Greeks call it thymos, smoke, rage.
愤怒就是你的天赋
And rage is your gift.
就像伟大的阿喀琉斯 永远不要放弃它
Like the great Achilles, never let it go.
它会助你成就伟业 我的冠军
It will carry you to greatness, my champion.
感谢你的邀请
Thank you for inviting me.
这真是莫大的荣幸
This is truly an honor.
听说你去过王宫
I hear you have talked the court.
是的 我们以前见过
Yes, we met before.
是吗
Have we?
很久以前
Long ago.
在哪里
Where?
我曾在您父亲的军队里服役 参加过非洲远征
I was in the service of your father's army on this African campaign.
你曾为我父亲效力
You served with my father.
啊
Oh.
我有幸读过他的冥想录
I had the privilege of reading his meditations.
最好的复仇就是不要变得和伤害你的人一样
The best revenge is to be unlike him who performed the injury.
听说你武装了半个帝国的军团
I hear you've been arming half the legions of the entire empire.
而你就在这里 在罗马
You've been here, now, in Rome.
你通过赞助角斗士来扩大影响力
You're gaining influence by sponsoring gladiators.
我是出于对这项运动的热爱
I do it for the love of the sport.
你从哪找到这些角斗士的
And where did you find these gladiators?
他们通常是战俘或流浪者
They're usually prisoners of war or vagrants.
你为何问这个
What do you ask?
人可以选择战斗并活下去
A man can choose to fight and stay alive.
生活和竞技场都是如此 不是吗
It's the same in life as it is in the arena, is it not?
这是谁
Who is this?
那是我父亲年轻时的样子
That is my father as a youth.
她有个孩子
She had a child.
这是众所周知的事
It's common knowledge.
康茂德被杀时 那男孩消失了
When commonness was killed, the boy disappeared.
那男孩很重要
Boy would care.
西拉会在意的
Silla would care.
更多的妻子
More wives!
毕竟他有着皇室血统
He was of a royal bloodline, after all.
那他的父亲是谁
And his father?
表面上是卢修斯·维鲁斯
Ostensibly, Lucius Verus.
你看 这是一桩政治婚姻
You see, it was an arranged marriage.
她才14岁
She was 14.
他对女人没兴趣
Females were not his taste.
反正有些日子是这样
No mind, some days.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
在罗马 你看 她有情人
By room, you see, she took lovers.
在罗马 真正的父亲是康茂德
And by room, the real father was commonness.
这大概就是爱情吧
It's probably love, you see.
如果他死了 一定会有遗骸
If he died, there has to be remains.
如果他还活着 他现在应该
And if he lived, that would make him about...
让我们算算
Well, let's work it out.
他死的时候大约12岁
He was about 12 when he died.
是的
Yes.
那么他现在应该
So that would make him...
再见 夫人
Bye, lady.
练习
practice.
我曾经去过
I used to go.
谢谢
Thank you.
夫人 你认识我吗
Lady, do you know me?
你有个家庭
You have a family.
一个妻子
A wife.
一个日神
A Rishan.
A Rishan?
她死在你丈夫的统领下
She was killed under your husband's command.
在草地上血流成河
From drowns in the turf blood.
而你却在这享受奢华生活
And yet you enjoy the pleasures of the cotton ceiling.
很多事你都不明白
There's much you do not understand.
公爵夫人
Duchess.
我不知道你以为我是谁
I do not know who you think I am.
我叫哈洛 我没有母亲 或者说记不得母亲
My name is Harlow, and I have no mother or mother I can remember.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
如果他在这里 我相信他会告诉你不要为他悲伤
If you were somewhere here, I feel sure he would tell you not to grieve him.
因为他已不是你送走的那个男孩
For he would not be the boy that you sent away.
那个男孩已经死了 你也许认为我一文不值
That boy is dead. You may think I have little worth.
你也许认为我背叛了你
You may think I betrayed you.
但我要你知道
But I need you to know,
如果你不给予母爱
if you will not have your mother's love
就拿出父亲的力量吧
and take your father's strength,
你需要它
you need it.
他的名字是马克西姆斯
His name was Maximus,
德西姆斯感动了我 他叫马克西姆斯
and Decimus moved me. His name was Maximus,
德西姆斯感动了我
and Decimus moved me.
我在你身上看到了他
And I see him in you.
出去
Get out.
我告诉你 我们必须立刻离开
I say to you, we must go at once.
你是被爱着的
It's just you were loved.
被我和你父亲所爱
By myself and by your father.
你的名字在他的名单上
Your name was on his list.
出去
Get out!
就剩这些活着的了
There's just this alive.
你确定吗
Are you certain?
是的
Yes.
我了解我的儿子
I know my son.
今晚我和他谈过了
I spoke to him tonight.
因为我的所作所为 他可能永远不会原谅我
He may be lost to me for what I did.
但他还活着
But he lives.
明天是比赛的第三天
The third day of the game is tomorrow.
大多数斗士都活不下来
Most fighters won't survive.
所以你必须帮忙
Okay, so you must help.
帮帮他 是的
Help him. Yes.
我那时辜负了他
I failed him then.
我知道我做错了
I know I did.
我这次不能再让他失望
I cannot fail him now.
娜奥米是个严厉的人
Naomi's an austere.
如果我们等几天...
If we wait a few days...
他那时可能已经死了
He could be dead by then.
我的命运啊
My kisses.
我愿意献出我的生命
I would willingly give my life from...
但我不会牺牲我的儿子
But I will not give my sons.
一
One.
二
Two.
再一个
And one.
再两个
And two.
再一个
And one.
去 去
Go, go.
一个人可能就这样倒下
One can fall like this.
就他一个
Just him.
你走
You go.
走
Go.
让我看看没有队友你能坚持多久
Let's see how far you can go on your own without your team.
准备好了吗
Ready?
一
One.
二
Two.
明白了
Got it.
来吧 继续
Come on. More.
继续
More.
只是醋而已 我的朋友
Just vinegar, my friend.
你不会再得到鸦片了
There will be no more opium for you.
痛苦的美丽在来世等着你
There is beauty of pain waiting for you in the next life.
我不明白你为什么这么渴望这个
I don't know why you are so pretty for eating this one.
罗比 你是个自由人吗
Are you a free man, Robbie?
不 我不是自由人 你呢 罗比
No. I'm not a free man. Are you a free man, Robbie?
自由
Free.
我是
I am.
我放下了剑 发誓再也不会拿起
I lay down my sword and I swore never to pick it up again.
你现在难道不是自己选择的吗
Didn't you choose this now?
是的
Yeah.
你以前的家在哪里
What was your home before?
但我不是
But I'm not.
为什么不回去
Why don't you go back?
我希望能回去
Wish I could.
我不是女人
I'm not a woman.
总是为了一个女人
It's always a woman, for once.
她来自意大利的布隆比诺
She's from Bloombdino, in Italy.
现在我们的儿子只会说拉丁语
So now, our sons, they speak only Latin.
我女儿说"啊 那里 蓝得像你的眼睛"
My daughter says, "Ah, it's there, it's blue as yours."
我们现在是机器人了
We are robots now.
我从小就听着祖父讲述的故事长大
I grew up hearing stories of my grandfather's knee.
他常说那个错误的梦想
He used to talk of the dream that was wrong.
如此脆弱 只能用耳语诉说
It was so fragile, you could only whisper it.
多么虚幻
What a vanish.
多么姐妹情深
What a sister.
一个错误 让所有人都能在荒芜的草地上生活 得到保护
A wrong where all could live on the foul lawn, be protected.
参议院的错误
Wrong with the Senate.
一个充满希望的错误
A wrong of hope.
你的祖父听起来是个危险的人
Your grandfather, he sounds like a dangerous man.
胜算对你不利
The odds are against you.
胜算总是对我不利
The odds are always against me.
别担心 老头
Don't worry, old man.
嘿
Hey?
你该休息了
You should get some rest.
明天你的士兵需要你的领导
Your men will need you to lead them tomorrow.
生存 生存
Survival! Survival!
以主的名义 我们庆祝新月光的荣耀
In the name of the Lord, we celebrate the glory of the new moonwalk.
愿主准备好听从我的命令
May the Lord just be ready to listen for my command.
团结一致
Stay together with
今天 我们重现萨拉米斯战役
Today, we relive the Battle of Salamis.
巨蛇击败了波斯人
The serpent passes the Persian.
奥塞尔
O'sell!
还有普尔
And Poole!
喔
Whoa!
准备开始了吗
Let's start, ready?
再来两次
And two more more times!
这边
Over here!
趴下
Get down!
这边
Over here!
准备跑
Ready to run!
冲啊
Let's run!
跑
Run!
一 二 三
One, two, three!
克里多利亚
Kridoria!
以皇帝的名义
In the name of the Emperor,
汉诺威获胜
the victor is Hanover!
谁干的
Who did this?
是我
It was me!
我干的
I did it!
盖塔会要你们所有人付出代价
Gaeta will want retribution for all of you.
你是在同一个地方
Did you learn to shoot the same place
学会射击和逃跑的吗 为什么是三声
you learned to escape, why three?
幸好不是我 否则我一定会找到你
Be glad it wasn't me or that, I would have found you.
是吗
Is it?
我有消息告诉你
I have news for you.
他来了 大人
He's here, sir.
哦 还在这里
Oh, still here.
又回到那个话题
Back to that.
好吧
Well.
是的 有新情况
Yeah, something is new.
你知道这里现在是我的房子
You know this is my house now.
你欠我超过一万第纳尔
Your debt to me is over 10,000 denarii.
你知道的
You know that.
我还有其他东西 牲畜
I have other things, cattle.
真相
Truth.
死亡
Death.
你想要什么
What do you want?
真相  我只要真相
Truth, that's what I want.
罗马城里发生的事  你都了如指掌
Nothing happens in Rome without your knowledge.
你得到了元老院的信任
You have the senator's trust.
也得到了罪人的信任
You have the sinner's trust.
更重要的是  你得到了我的信任
More importantly, you have my trust.
你想要我效忠于你
You wish my loyalty?
我掌控你的家族
I own your house.
你的家族
Your house.
我要你的忠诚
I want your loyalty.
我  我听说有人密谋推翻至高无上者
I, I have heard of a plot to dethrone the elixir.
是的
Yes.
但计划已经推迟了
But the plan has been delayed.
我很高兴今晚能从竞技场救出阿特尔
I'm glad the ater is to be rescued from the arena tonight.
我什么都不知道
I know no one.
我知道缘由  也知道是谁
I know why, I know who.
帕特
Pat.
快点
Quickly.
第一场开始
Open for the first job!
第二场开始
Open for the second job!
夫人  请跟我们来
My lady, come with us.
多亏了萨拉克斯和马克罗努斯
Thanks to the civic virtue of men
这样的忠臣
like Thrax and Macronus,
你们的叛乱已经暴露了
your insurrection has been revealed.
罗马赐予你的荣誉和尊严
The honor, the dignitas that Rome has bestowed
因你的背叛而全部丧失
upon you, all this you have forfeited by your treachery.
盖特  你要拷打我就尽管来
Please, ever, Gator, torture me if you want,
但别对我说教
but do not lecture me.
你的名字将被遗忘
Your name will be forgotten!
从历史上抹去
Lost to history.
你完了  将军
You are damned, General.
你被爱戴
You're loved.
你毁了我
You damned me.
我不在乎
I don't care.
时间会抹去一切
Everything is forgotten in time.
帝国会衰落  皇帝也会
Empires fall, so do emperors.
何必等待
Why wait?
我要砍了他
I will cut him.
来吧  来吧
Come, come.
他必须公开处死
His death must be public.
公开
Public?
绞死
Hang!
他的死亡将使这座城市
His death fails, and his city takes
刺痛我的心
a cruise of my heart.
听我说  要么活着  要么我就杀了他们
Truth, survive, or I will take them away!
好
Yes.
谢谢你  马克罗努斯
Thank you, Macronus.
天啊
God.
这些日子以来  我开始把你视为
In these last days, I have come to think of you
不只是臣民  而是真正的朋友
not as a subject, but as a true friend.
谢谢
Thank you.
非常感谢  但作为朋友
Thank you so much, but as a friend,
我必须劝你谨慎行事
I must counsel caution
卡西斯是罗马的英雄
that cases are a hero of Rome,
他的行为却与贼寇基督徒无异
whose fiction is for thieves, Christians.
太普通了
It's too common.
他是叛徒
He is a traitor.
必须死
He must die.
我同意
I agree.
但众神仍在
But the gods reside.
他的命运  由您决定
His fate, in the cause of you.
让众神来决定吧
Let the gods decide.
昨晚我梦见了黑暗的河流
You know, last night I woke dreaming of the dark river.
这次  第一只眼睛正在渡河
This time, the first eye was crossing it.
嗯
Hmm.
你知道我来自何方
You know where I come from.
渡河象征着宽恕
Oh, crossing a rewrite represents forgiveness,
象征着救赎
represents salvation.
在我的故乡  这意味着你已经死了
Oh, where I come from, it means you're already dead.
当我看到它时  我并不害怕
As I saw it, I was not afraid.
因为有人在这边等着我
For someone who was waiting for me, I'm here on this side.
此人是谁
Who is this man?
斯克拉图斯
Scratched out.
马克西姆斯
Maximus.
我曾见过那火焰
I saw the fire once.
那是如此壮丽
It was magnificent.
我在军团的时间比他晚
Hmm, you know, my time at the unrenewed was after his,
但军营里仍在谈论他
but when he still talked of him in his bus,
谈论他的事迹
spoke of him, what he did.
我见过他一面
I met him once.
他很和善
He was kind.
不向任何人低头
Bowed to no one.
跟我来
Come with me.
叛逆的角斗士死后
Well, a rebel gladiator dies.
我们将他们葬在这里
We bury them here.
我们今生所为  必将永垂不朽
What we do in life, that cause an ontology.
阿金托女士  斯塔特女士
Mrs. Argento, Mrs. Starter.
在那儿
There.
举起手来
Hands up.
因背叛帝国与皇帝
For his treason against the lives of the emperors
以及罗马国家的尤斯塔斯将军阿卡西亚
and the Roman state general Eustace Acacia,
人民的敌人
an enemy of the people.
愿你胜利
Be victors.
将军
General.
来自被征服之城新米底亚
From the vanquished city of New Medea,
胜者已两度征服了鉴赏家
the victor was two conquests in the connoisseur.
去吧
Go now.
愿你胜利
Be victors.
来吧
Come on!
主啊  我的荣耀尽归于您
Oh Lord, any honor I have, I will give it to you.
太迟了
It's too late.
罗马叛徒还是蛮族英雄
The Roman traitor or the barbarian hero.
让众神来决定
Let the gods decide.
等等
Wait.
等等  等等
Wait, wait!
等等
Wait!
我是一个容器
I am a vessel.
填满我的注射器
Fill the infonjings.
与背叛者战斗
And fight with the betrayer.
天啊
Oh God.
拿起来
Pick it up!
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
卢修斯·瓦雷维斯
Lucius Varevis.
卢修斯已经举手了
Lucius has raised his hand.
他投降了
He has surrendered.
让众神来决定
Let the gods decide.
众神已经做出了判决
The gods have rendered their judgment.
按你说的做
Do what you ask.
但在我死前你要知道
But on my death you have to know,
我爱你  约瑟夫之母
I love you, Mother Yusef.
还有你的父亲
And your father.
卢修斯  我愿为他而死
Lucius, I would have died for him.
出去
Get out!
救命
Help!
滚出去
Get out!
我要杀了他
I'm gonna kill him.
我做不到
I can't!
不  杀了他
No! Kill him!
杀了他
Kill him!
告诉他
Tell him!
我要点火了
I got a fuse!
不
No!
我要点火了
I got a fuse!
抓住你了
I got you!
这对你来说太便宜了
That's what be too good for you.
这就是我们的真相  就在这里
Is this our own truth, it's here all!
告诉我
Tell me!
如果他的生命毫无价值  你的又值几何
If his life has no value, what in yours were?
众神已经开口
The gods have spoken!
我的死期
My death!
为了安全起见  我们该回宫了
For our own safety, we should return to the palace.
退后  退后
Stay back, stay back!
我们达成了交易
We had a bargain.
我把他交给了你
I gave him to you.
你让他活了下来
You let him live.
你得到了你想要的
And you got what you wanted.
我总能得到想要的
I always get what I want.
你为什么要让他活着
Why did you let him live?
你买的是角斗士  不是奴隶
You bought a gladiator, not a slave.
我自有主张
My will is my own.
你的血统有多高贵
How blue is your blood?
或许你胸膛里跳动的是罗马人的心
Perhaps the heart of a Roman feeds in that chest.
罗马最宏伟的建筑  竞技场
The greatest temple Rome ever built, the Colosseum,
因为这就是他们信仰的  权力
because this is what they believe in, power.
他们聚集在这里  看强者击倒弱者
They gather here to watch the strong strike down.
一定还有别的
There has to be something else.
没有别的
There is nothing else.
一定还有另一个罗马
There has to be another Rome.
没有另一个罗马
There is no other Rome.
罗马的梦想  这梦想
The dream, the dream of Rome.
不过是老人的幻想
It's an old man's fantasy.
你是谁
Who are you?
你用罗马名字换掉的本名是什么
What was your name before you traded it for a Roman one?
你永远也不会知道
You'll never know.
我有我的命运
I have a destiny.
众神把你送到了我身边
The gods delivered you to me.
你将成为我的工具
You will be my instrument.
无论今生来世  我都不会成为你的工具
I will never be your instrument in this life for the next.
那不会是我的命运
That will not be my destiny.
但我会看着你的结局
But I will see your end.
我还能怎么办
What else could I do?
他和那个贱人会害死我们的
He and his bitch will cause him to kill us.
你没听到吗
Don't you hear them?
他们在叫嚣着要我们的人头
They're calling for our heads.
佩托利人会镇压这场暴乱
The Petolians will put down this crap
就像镇压其他暴乱一样
like they have every other.
谁挑起了这一切
Who brought this all up?
肮脏的家伙
Filthy guy!
也许你该带约翰去别处
Perhaps you should take Johness elsewhere
安抚他
to comfort him.
我原谅我兄弟的失态
I forgive my brother's outburst.
腰胯间的疾病已经蔓延到了他的大脑
The disease that infects his loins is spread to his brain.
一天比一天严重
Every day gets worse.
我会跟他讲道理
I will reason with him.
我看到你了
I see you.
得走了  得走了
Gotta go, gotta go.
来  站起来
Go on, stand up.
起来  起来  不是你
Get up, get up, not you.
好
All right.
现在听我说
Now, listen to me.
怎么了
What's the matter?
我从来都没有自己的东西
Nothing's ever mine.
一切都是我们共有的  从在娘胎里就是如此
Everything is ours always, even in the womb.
他试图夺走我的脐带
He tried to get my umbilicus
这样我就不会再有头发了
so that I couldn't have any more hair.
你还记得这事吗
You remember that, do you?
当然记得
Certainly.
坐
Sit.
这事无法忘记
One cannot forget.
我的良心在谴责我
My conscience compels me.
为什么
Why?
坐下
Sit.
你弟弟打算指控你
Your brother means to blame you
当着整个元老院的面
in front of the entire Senate.
但不是我干的
But I did not do it.
街头的混乱已经发生了
Well, what's happening in the streets is the chaos.
他在撒谎
He's lying.
没有什么证词比
No testimony can be more damning
兄弟互相指认更具杀伤力
than one brother against another.
这是谎言
That's a lie.
他总是在说谎
He always lies.
他说起话来很有说服力
He can be very persuasive.
那他们会怎么对我
So, what will they do to me?
我不敢想象  但你可以想象
I don't dare imagine, but imagine this.
他们会怎么对托马斯
What will they do to Thomas?
这由你决定
It's your decision.
弟弟
Brother.
放下刀
Put down the blade.
你在撒谎
You lie.
给我
Give it to me.
你总是在撒谎
You always lie.
给我
Give it to me.
看着我
Look at me.
谎言
Lie!
让我打破这个魔咒
Let me break this spell.
谎言
Lie!
打破这个咒语
Break this spell.
我一直在保护你
I've always protected you.
因为我爱你
Because I love you.
回来吧
Come back.
帮帮我
Help me.
托马斯
Thomas.
真想不到命运会把我们带到这里
Never could have imagined the fates would lead us here.
但我们现在确实在这里
And yet here we are.
一切都回到了原点
Everything that's brought us full circle,
你把我送走了 而他有信念
you set me away and he had faith.
你把我带回了他死去的地方
You brought me back to the very ground where he died.
这枚戒指属于我父亲
This ring belonged to my father.
他把它给了你父亲马克西姆斯 作为信任的象征
He gave it to your father, Maximus, as a token of trust.
我把它给了卡修斯 表彰他的勇气
I gave it to Cassius for his valor.
这枚戒指属于我的妻子
This ring belonged to my wife.
我会把它和你的戒指一起戴着
I shall wear it next to yours.
我为她的遭遇深感抱歉
I'm truly sorry for her cases.
但我无法看到那个人
But I could not see the man.
那是个士兵
It was a soldier from...
有个计划
There was a plan.
他正在奥斯提亚集结军队支持达里乌斯·塞克斯图斯
He was readying troops at Ostian to the Galant of Dereis Sextus.
那些军队将反抗皇帝
Troops he was to lead against the emperors.
阿卡修斯 马克西姆斯 马库斯·奥勒留
Aacacius, Maximus, Marcus Aurelius.
他们为罗马而生为罗马而死
They lived and died for her own.
我们都是如此
We all do.
他们真的想杀你吗
Is it true they attempt to kill you?
自从我父亲去世那天起 就总有人想取我性命
One man or another has had a sword against my neck since the day my father died.
但现在找到你了 这些都不重要了
But now that I've found you, it doesn't matter.
我不再害怕
I am not afraid.
我已经习惯失去所爱之人
I've become well versed in losing the things that I love.
但既然找到你了 我不想再失去你
But now that I've found you, I have no desire to lose you again.
时间像他吗
Is time like him?
我活着
I live.
骄傲地
Proud.
我没有那个力量
I do not have the strength.
我希望是真的
I wish that were true.
我希望能让你逃离这里
I wish I were telling you to flee this place.
走吧
Go now.
暂时离开
Stray for the moment.
我已召集元老院任命我的第一执政官
A zebra! I have convened the senate to appoint my first consul
并授予他权力来管理
and bestow upon him the power to administer
帝国的军事和民事事务
the military and civic functions of the empire.
我任命公民唐达斯
I name Citizen Dondas!
向唐达斯致敬
Hail Dondas!
Hail Dondas?
向唐达斯致敬
Hail Dondas!
作为第二执政官 我任命
As second consul, I name
公民
Citizen
马克洛努斯
Macronus!
向马克洛努斯致敬
Hail Macronus!
将举行凯旋游行庆祝
There will be a triumphal parade to celebrate.
会有竞技表演
There will be games
和大规模处决
and mass executions.
帝国万岁
Long live the empire.
坐下
Sit down.
我凭借
I happen to have
好运和一点技巧
with good fortune and not a little skill.
把剩余的皇帝抓来了
The remaining emperors here.
我可以与之讲道理
I can speak logic to it.
平息街头的疯狂
And tame the madness in the street.
但是
But,
我们仍需秩序
we still order.
我必须掌握权力
I must have power
统领彼得鲁利亚军队
and command over the Petrurian army.
巴拉克
Balak!
或者汉德
Or hand.
您卑微的仆人
Your humble servant.
放下你的手
Put your hands down.
你可以坐下了
You can sit down.
罗马必须陨落
Rome must fall.
我只需轻轻一推
I need to only give it a push.
罗马陨落之后呢
And after Rome falls?
然后怎样
What then?
你真是你父亲的孩子
You are your father's child.
他对罗马的梦想从来不是梦
His dream of Rome was never a dream.
那是虚构的
It was a fiction.
最好的复仇就是变得与伤害你的人不同
The best revenge is to become unlike the one who did the injury.
我让自己变得与你父亲不同
I have made myself unlike your father.
他谈论梦想 我讲述真相
He spoke of dreams, I speak of truth,
在我的罗马中唯一的真相
and the only truth in my Rome
就是强者的法则
is the law of the strongest.
我曾被
I was owned
一个皇帝奴役
by an emperor.
现在我统治着一个帝国
Now I control an empire.
除了罗马 哪里能让人做到这一点
Where else but in Rome can a man do that?
你认出你父亲在我身上留下的印记了吗
Do you recognize your father's mark on me?
如果你
If there is anything,
在最后时刻需要什么
you need in these last hours,
我们会提供
we will provide.
你的死亡将为我登上王位扫清道路
Your death will clear my path to the throne.
明天将会有角斗表演
Tomorrow there will be games,
在那里我将胜出
and at them I will prevail.
罗比
Robbie.
你能在明早前把消息送到奥斯提亚吗
Can you get me the message to Osti by morning?
奥斯提亚有什么
What is it, Osti?
那里有一支军队
There is an army.
我请求你冒险 我的朋友
I'm asking you to risk yourself, my friend,
为了更伟大的事业
on the surface of something greater.
骑马去奥斯提亚
Ride to Ostia.
把这枚戒指交给达里乌斯·塞克斯图斯将军 你听好了吗
Take this ring to General Darius Sextus, are you listening?
达里乌斯·塞克斯图斯会认出这是阿卡修斯的戒指
Darius Sextus, you will know as a Cacius' ring.
那么 大人 我该说什么
And, uh, what shall I say, sir?
把戒指带给他
Send me with this ring.
我是卢修斯·费里斯·奥勒留
I am Lucius Ferris Aurelius.
罗马王子
Prince of Rome.
告诉他我正召集军队保卫新共和国
Tell him I am summoning the army to the defense of a new republic.
要我考验你吗 要
Shall I test you? Yes.
要我吗 要
Shall I? Yes.
罗比 我需要你的钥匙
Robbie, I need your keys.
去吧
Go!
给我回来
Come back!
谁给你的这个
Who gave you this?
罗塞里利乌斯的卢修斯
Lucius the Roserilius.
罗马的王子
The Prince of Rome.
大人 这是我的街头礼物
My street gift, sir.
只要她还活着 你就永远不得安宁
Until she dies, you will never know peace.
永远
Ever.
拉夫堡的民众 死亡会激起暴民
The people of Loughborough, death will incite the mob.
如果她死了 街上的民众起义绞死她
If she dies and the streets rise up and hang her,
我要让他们明白卡拉卡拉的想法
I shall drill into them Caracalla's head,
民众会赞颂我 因为我的朋友是政治
and the people shall acclaim me that my friend is politics.
开始吧 好
Shall we? Yes.
今天将是你最后一战 冠军
Today will be your last fight, champion.
我们的主人已经赐予你
And our master has bestowed on you
象征自由的木剑
the wooden sword of freedom.
但你必须先赢得它
But you have to earn it first.
今天 你要为你的母亲而战
Today, you're going to defend your mother.
好一招 这一剑 这还是一剑
What a steal, a point, this is still a point.
为我而战
Fight for me.
以卡拉卡拉皇帝的指控为名
In honor of the accusations of Emperor Caracalla,
第一议员多洛斯和第二议员马克罗诺斯
First Council, Dolos, and Second Council, Macronos,
作为她密谋反对帝国的惩罚
and as punishment for her conspiracy against the Empire,
由于她对皇帝御用拉比的诽谤
for her caliphes against the Emperor's imperial rabbi,
以及煽动军事叛乱
and for fomenting military mutiny,
连同她的希望 女王将面临神圣的审判
along with her hope, the Queen will face divine justice
死于禁卫军之手
at the hands of the Praetorian Guard.
我不是将军 但我们都是老兵
I'm not a general, but we are old soldiers.
直到现在 我们战斗的目的不过是
And up until now, we have fought for nothing more
为了多活一天
than another day's survival.
你要我们做什么
What will you have us do?
如果你们不愿参与这场战斗
Well, you can return to yourselves if you do not wish
可以选择离开
to fight this battle.
或者 你们可以加入我 为超越这些墙壁的
Or, you can join me and fight for a freedom
自由而战
far beyond these walls.
曾经有一个时代 荣誉意味着面对敌人
There once was a time when honor met the enemy,
曾经有一个时代 在罗马荣誉意味着一切
there once was a time when honor meant something in Rome.
在这个罗马 我不再相信这些还存在
In this Rome, I no longer believe that exists.
我们必须找回荣誉
We must find it.
且记住
And know this,
有死亡的地方 便没有我们
where death is, we are not.
有我们的地方 便没有死亡
Where we are, death is not.
为何是我的剑
Why my sword?
直取另一个
Straight to another!
不要说皇帝不懂仁慈
Let it not be said that the emperor is not merciful.
女王将获准选择一名
The queen will be granted a single
角斗士对抗禁卫军之神
gladiator to defend her against the praetorian god.
冠军 哈达姆
The champion, Hadam!
骑兵队 立刻镇压这场骚乱
Someone in the cavalry put this down at once.
这是战争 真正的战争
This is the war, real war!
阿尔切斯的军队已逼近罗马城外 大人
The army of Arces is advancing just outside of Rome, sir.
我们还能打败他们
We can still out-fight them.
他们只有五千兵力 不会更多
They have only 5,000 troops, no more.
我们有多少人
How many are we?
六千 或许更多
6,000, perhaps more.
骑兵去城门守住
Ride to the gate and hold us.
快逃
Go for the escape!
十八
eighteen?
把球给我 我的孩子 回家去吧
Give me the ball. Go home, my son.
你看到天空了吗
Will you see the sky?
老大
Boss!
这野蛮人怎么杀不死
Will nothing kill this barbarian?
我名叫卢修斯·巴里斯·奥勒留
Name is Lucius Barris Aurelius.
成为皇帝不只靠血统
A man did not become emperor by bloodline alone,
必须用武力夺取 用武力保住
must be taken by force and kept by force.
你就是这样的人吗
Are you such a man as this?
我不为权力而战
I don't fight for power.
我为解放罗马而战 让它摆脱你这样的人 回归人民
I fight to free Rome from men like you and to return it to them.
众神亲临 罗马重生
The gods themselves, what Rome reborn,
他们派我来完成这个使命
they sent me to fulfill that task.
你的骨头呢 第二个来杀你的人
And what of your bones, second here to kill you?
啊
Ah!
是时候结束这一切了 巴卡拉
It's time to end this, Baccarat!
啊
D'ah!
住手
Don't!
停下
Stop!
列克预测
Lec forecasts
直接
Straight up.
我的孩子
My son.
你们期待我的演说
You look to me to speak.
我除了说我们都经历了太多苦难外 不知该说什么
I know not what to say other than we have all known too much, Dad.
但不能再为暴政流血了
But no more blood be spilled in the name of tyranny.
我的祖父马库斯·奥勒留谈到过罗马的梦想
My grandfather Marcus Aurelius talked of the dream that would be wrong.
一个我的父亲马克西姆斯·德西姆斯·梅里迪乌斯为之牺牲的梦想
A dream that my father, Maximus Decimus Meridius, died for.
一个理想
An ideal.
一座为众人而建的城市 一处庇护需要帮助之人的避难所
A city for the many and a refuge for those in need.
一个值得为之奋斗的家园
A home worth fighting for.
一个马克西姆斯用毕生守护的家园
A home that Maximus spent his life defending.
梦想已失
A dream is lost.
但黎明将至
A day awake.
让我们共同建造这个梦想
We build that dream together.
你们意下如何
What say you?
娜拉
Nala.
父亲 告诉我该怎么做
Speak to me, father.
ed3000.cc 原创翻译出品  参与：贾婷、会飞的猪仔  校对：巴萨姆